人人影視
YYeTs.com
本字幕由人人影視字幕組翻譯
禁止用作任何商業盈利行為
翻譯： 圈圈     阿髻     胖兔純     蘇小黛
翻譯： Kiko      DustD     MythCreator
時間軸： 濃子   萌    校對： 蘇小黛   胖兔純
后期： 孤帆    總監： 米小勒   胖兔純
塞勒姆
第一季  第三集
《塞勒姆》前情提要
Previously on "Salem"
艾薩克
Isaac?
私通者艾薩克
Isaac the fornicator.
別以為回到塞勒姆就能遠離戰爭
Coming home to Salem to get out of the war
這就像為了躲雨而一頭跳進大海
is like jumping in the ocean to get out of the rain.
你現在不能離開塞勒姆
You can't leave Salem just yet.
有些東西你得看看
Something you've got to see.
有人破壞了我們的祭祀圈
Someone broke our circle.
誰看見了我們
Who saw us?
我不知道
I do not know.
我一直在等著你
I waited for you.
年復一年
Years and years.
跟我走吧
Come with me.
我不能  不可能了
I can't. It's impossible.
大祭典已經開始
The grand rite has begun,
土地渴求著純潔鮮血的滋養
and the earth cries out for innocent blood.
我很清楚自己的職責
I know well my duties.
我活著就是為了有一天
The only thing that keeps me alive
能親眼見到
is the look on your face
約翰·奧登發現你真正身份時你臉上的表情
when John Alden finds out what you really are.
父親  您認識布里奇特
Father, you know Bridget.
您怎能認為她犯下了這種罪孽
How could you think her guilty of this?
我怎么認為無關緊要
It isn't a matter of what I think.
看你干的好事
What a mess you've made of things.
我不想在這里看到你
I don't want you here.
我差點就相信你了
I almost believe you.
你真美
You're so beautiful.
人類的戰爭不足為懼
"Fear no man's war,
只有來自地獄的戰火能摧毀塞勒姆
for only a war from hell could destroy Salem."
魔鬼絕不會輕易讓我們
The devil was never going to
在這建立應許之地  它必將掀起一場戰爭
let a promised land be built here without a battle.
你知道埋在這的女人幾乎都死于什么嗎
Do you know what killed nearly every woman buried here?
愛情
Love.
擁有致命惡意的巫師...
And witches armed with deadly malice...
大多數都死于分娩  所以說愛情之于女人
Most died in childbirth. So love is to a woman...
便是這場戰役中最為狠毒陰險的武器
...are the most malignant and insidious weapons in that battle...
就好比戰爭之于男人
...what war is to a man.
-這場戰爭中  -是他們能做的最致命的事
- ...that war  - The most deadly thing, they'll do.
為了一個民族的身體與靈魂
for the body and the soul of a nation.
只有傻子才會迫不及待的奔向戰爭...
Only a fool runs quickly to war...
設想這些在暗處的敵人...
Imagine a foe you can't see...
-或者愛情  -擁有未知的武器...
- or love. - armed with weapons unknown...
我可以教給你...
I can teach you...
看上去卻和常人別無二致
...and the ability to appear as anyone.
關于生命和死亡還有許多介于二者之間的東西
...about life and death and many things in between.
住手  快住手  住手
Stop it! Just stop it! Stop.
勿輕言  否則汝必招致審判
Judge not, lest ye be judged.
*擂我戰鼓*
*Pound me the witch drums*
*鼓鳴震天*
*Witch drums*
*擂我戰鼓*
*Pound me the witch drums*
*鼓鳴震天*
*The witch drums*
*寧入地獄*
*Better pray for hell*
*不留人間*
*Not hallelujah*
燒死在地獄里
Burn in hell!
罪惡
Sin!
放心  布里奇特小姐
Be assured, Mrs. Bridget --
為你哭泣之人
ones that are weepin'
遠比唾棄詛咒之人多
far outnumber the ones that might spit or curse.
燒死在地獄里  燒吧
Burn in hell! Burn!
多給那人點錢讓他把尸體
You would do well to pay that boy extra
送去更遠的地方就更好了
to take them bodies a more circuitous route.
人們的圍觀是我們烈火的燃料
Spectacle is fuel for our fire.
質疑可是富人和受寵者的特權
And doubt is indulged by the rich and spoiled only.
記住  你以前可既不富有  也沒人寵溺
Mind that you was born neither.
讓我與你一同死去吧  而后我將重生
"Give me to die with thee that I may rise to a new life,
我希望自己的罪惡和自私  都被
"for I wish to be as dead and buried to sin,
長埋地下...
to selfishness..."
辛苦了  牧師
By all means, Reverend...
千萬別說任何祈禱安慰或者鼓勵的話
Do not offer prayer or comfort or words of encouragement.
對  就這樣如一座不知所措的雕像般
No, stand as a bewildered statue
站在塞勒姆的人民中間
amongst the people of Salem
什么都不說  什么都不做
and offer them absolutely nothing.
那您想讓我怎么做
What would you have me do?
我讓你來是干什么的
What I brought you here to do.
在我們需要指引時幫助我們啊
Guide and support us in our great hour of need.
用你充滿智慧的言辭溫暖我們的心靈
Warm our hearts with your words of wisdom.
讓大家知道除掉惡魔是上帝的旨意
Assure us it is God's will we do in ferreting out the devil.
或者至少...
Or at the very, very least...
祈禱吧
Pray.
悲慘的一天啊
Tragic day.
雖然悲慘  但有必要
Tragic but necessary.
很遺憾這是必要的
Tragically necessary.
眾人的哀悼可以讓你暫時歇口氣了吧
Surely, the grieving of the masses gives you pause.
大多數人唾棄詛咒她
Most spit and curse
同時還召喚地獄之火的焚燒
while summoning the burning flames of hell.
也有人
There are also
為她哭泣  覺得絞死她毫無根據
those who weep for her and find her hanging unfounded.
區區幾個人  不足為意
Not enough to divert our intentions.
要讓眾人的恐慌不斷加劇才算成功
A panic's success relies on its escalation.
大祭典已經開始
The grand rite has begun.
我們需要尋找下一個受害者
We look to our next victim.
我的一切反對
And that I disagree,
如此強烈表示出我的不贊同
that I strenuously and most vehemently oppose
對你毫無意義可言嗎
means nothing to you?
我們祭祀時被人看見了
We were seen at our sabbat.
你竟然還這么公然行事
And you throw caution to the wind.
那你查出看見我們的人了嗎
And have you identified who saw us?
如果你能完成這點簡單的任務
Perhaps your disagreements and vehement opposition
或許你的不同意見和強烈反對
might hold more weight if you could be relied on
能多一些分量
to complete a simple task.
祝你今天愉快  霍爾
Good day, Hale.
我要怎么做才能得到救贖
What must I do to be saved?
沒有比這更重要的問題了
It is impossible to ask a more weighty question.
恐怕我們都將永恒逝去
Lest we perish eternally.
感覺如何
How's it feel?
什么感覺如何
How does what feel?
兩天之內殺死兩個無辜之人
Killing two innocents in as many days.
-證據指向畢謝普小姐  -孤兒院出事了
- The evidence against Miss Bishop. - The orphanage!
來人啊  他們在洗劫孤兒院
Help! They're looting the orphanage!
出去
Get out!
這不是你的
It's not yours!
滾...
Get...
下一槍就是你的腦袋了
Next one's to your head.
你還好嗎
Are you okay?
太可怕了  太可怕了
It's awful. It's too awful.
出什么事了
W-what's happened?
盜賊們來搶劫孤兒院
Thieves have come to ransack the orphanage
把這兒的守護者絞死  如今大家嘗到滋味了吧
now that the town sees fit to hang its guardian.
冷靜點  孩子
Easy, son.
這都是巫師恐慌造成的
This is what comes of your witch panic.
你還好嗎
Are you all right?
這都是你的錯  還有他
This is your fault! And his.
原諒她  她受驚了
Forgive her. She's distraught.
我沒說錯
I'm right!
送我回家
See me home.
上尉  如果你不介意
Captain, if you wouldn't mind, hmm?
當然可以
Yes. Of course.
他們把她帶去哪里了
Where have they taken her?
埋葬被遺棄者的污穢之所
Foul spot where they rest the unwanted.
很糟糕嗎
Is it very terrible?
是的
Yes.
謝謝你
Thank you...
感謝你的勇敢與坦誠
for your heroism and your candor.
歡迎  歡迎  歡迎
Welcome, welcome, welcome!
來杯茶嗎
A cup of tea?
-來口波特酒  -沒空
-A touch of port? -No time.
在樹林看見我們的是誰
Who saw us in the woods?
是擁有烙印之人
It was...he who is marked.
他的眉上烙著"F"
He of the "F" that furrows his brow.
-艾薩克  -私通者
-Issac? -The fornicator.
那個蠢貨
The idiot.
還有一件事
One more thing.
艾薩克并非獨自一人
Isaac was not alone.
還有誰跟他一起
Who else was with him?
我不知道
I don't know.
我看不清那張臉
I could not make out the face.
你不知道
You don't know.
你有何用
What good are you?
看不見的鬼眼
A seer who can't see.
我的法術并不精確
It's not an exact art.
看出來了
Evidently not.
有人嗎
Hello?
那是什么鬼地方
What the hell was that place?
彼得魯斯的窩棚
The shack belongs to Petrus,
他是野生及馴養動物的專家
an expert on creatures both feral and otherwise.
它們看起來是死的  但卻不是
Yeah, well, they looked dead...until they didn't.
死去的動物
No, dead animal
可傷不到像你這樣的老兵  上尉
could threaten a storied soldier such as yourself, captain.
要是被施了什么未知的法術  就有可能了
It could, if powered by forces we don't understand.
-比如  -巫術
-Such as? -Witchcraft.
-胡說  -是嗎
-Nonsense. -Is it?
你很了解他嗎  這個彼得魯斯
You know him well, this Petrus?
沒有比彼得魯斯更普通的人了
You'll find no man more ordinary than Petrus.
說他平凡都高估他的激情了
To say that he's mundane is to overstate his passion.
那是什么普通的任務讓你來到森林深處
And what ordinary task brought you deep into the forest
尋求他平凡的建議
to seek his mundane counsel?
別激動  孩子
Easy, son...
不然我可能都要懷疑
Or I might suspect your presence here
你的出現也并非偶然了
as more than a coincidence,
也許你有你的理由
That, perhaps, for reasons of your own
我相信你不希望我問起
about which I'm sure you'd rather I not inquire,
你怕是跟蹤我來此的吧
you might have followed me here.
你對小女這般仁慈
And what a shame...
我卻讓懷疑之心遮蔽了感激之意
to have suspicion overtake the grace I owe
真是令人遺憾
for the kindness you showed my daughter.
就算是扯平了吧
Consider it repaid.
也好
Right.
喬治  不是吧
George, really.
你連個孩子都不如
You are worse than a child.
它聽從我的吩咐  不聽你的
He serves at my behest, not yours.
你是沒法讓它出來的
He won't come out for you.
安靜點  小家伙
There, there, little man.
不用理會這個老怪物
Oh, pay the beast no mind.
先歇息  稍后我再來喂你
Rest now, and I'll see to your feeding later.
艾薩克把先生的藥劑拿來了
Isaac's brung the master's potions.
讓他等等
Tell him to wait.
喬治
Ohh, George.
你的睡衣都被嘔吐物徹底弄臟了
Your nightdress thoroughly drenched in sick.
今天就穿著它吧  親愛的
Stew in that for the day, my sweet.
給西布里先生的
For Mr. Sibley.
你要是早點來就好了
Oh, and not a moment too soon.
他現在狀態不太好
Just now, he suffered a fit of sorts.
如果您不介意的話  夫人
If you don't mind me saying so, ma'am,
我想說這真是您一直承受著的重擔
It's a burden you've took on...
一份不能言說  只能獨自承受的重荷
A burden and load, carried out without cry or complaint.
我的擔子跟塞勒姆的沒法比
My burdens can't compare to that of salem itself.
廣場上的氣氛如今怎么樣了
How do you find the spirits on the square?
消沉  夫人  非常消沉
Low, ma'am. Awful low.
或許這么想能聊以慰藉
Perhaps there is solace to be found
畢竟我們都曾承受過更糟的狀況
in remembrance of times when we've both shouldered worse.
誰能想到僅僅一晚
Who could have imagined that a single night
影響會如此之大呢
could have consequence for so many?
不是所有的傷疤都能被看到
Not all scars can be seen.
但它們卻切實存在著
But they exist nonetheless.
第二天一早  她走了
Next morning, she was gone.
逃離了這里  就這么消失了
Run away and disappeared.
你心愛的艾比
Oh, your sweet abby.
我得承認  有時候會想
I'll admit to wondering on occasion
如果有天能再見到她會是什么樣
What it might be like to one day see her again
會想  如果聽說了她的境況
Or know of her or hear her fate.
會是好事還是更糟呢
Would it be better or so much worse?
我向你保證  艾薩克
I can assure you, Isaac...
如果你還能再見到她
If you were to see her again,
你會發現那些感覺被埋葬得太深
you would find those feelings buried too deeply
已然無法復燃了
for hope of resurrection.
再見  艾薩克
Good afternoon, Isaac.
告辭  夫人
G'day, ma'am.
那是什么
What is that?
那是什么  你要干什么
What is that? What are you... what are you doing?
別  求你
Please. Please.
你在樹林里看到了什么
What did you see in the woods?
我們知道你不是只身一人
We knew you weren't alone.
我們知道
We know!
我們知道  我們知道
We know! We know!
還有誰在  還有誰在
Who was there?! Who was there?!
只有我一個人
I was alone!
弄干凈了
Get it all.
千萬別留下線索
Want no trace of our efforts.
要查也只能查到他一個人
The fault must lie with him alone.
把這些放進他口袋
And put these in his pockets.
如果要指證他是巫師
If he's to be found a witch,
那牧師一定會需要證據
The good reverend will require proof...
決定他命運的證據  懂嗎
...evidence to seal his fate, hmm?
怎么了
What is it?
我看到的是同情嗎
Is this sympathy that I'm sensing?
一個流浪漢對另一個流浪漢的同情
One outcast to the other?
你是這么想的嗎  老怪物
Is that what you feel, you decrepit deformity?
瑪麗
Mary!
現在連你都敢質疑我了
So now even you would question me?
照我說的做
Do as you're told!
你偉大的瑪麗知道眼看著女巫們被燒死是什么感覺嗎
Does your great Mary know what it is to watch witches burn?
她對傳統一屑不顧
Nothing of the old ways
只顧著鞭策我們向新的方向前進
while she's whipping us toward the new.
給他下個瘋狂咒
A spell of vitae cupido,
然后將他送去鎮上
And then we send him to the one place in town
他絕對不允許進入的地方
That will certainly deny him entrance.
應該會引起他們的注意
That should get their attention.
你哭了
You're crying.
沒有
I'm not.
你就是在哭
You are.
怎么了
What's wrong?
他們連畢謝普小姐那樣的人都要絞死
If they can hang a woman like miss Bishop,
那我這樣的人怎么辦
What does that mean for someone like me?
你不會有事的
Nothing is going to happen to you.
你怎么知道
How can you be so sure?
昨天他們還把我推到那個路易斯面前呢
Just yesterday, it was me that they put before the Lewis girl.
如果我被指控  你會站出來嗎
Would you have come forward had I been accused?
我做的一切都嚴守程序
I follow every protocol.
我遵從父親教給我的每一個字
I adhere to every letter of what my father taught me.
沒有人會被定罪  除非有無可爭議的證據
No one is convicted without incontrovertible evidence.
所以你確信畢謝普小姐是個女巫
So you're certain miss Bishop was a witch?
我確信..
I am certain...
那些證據
of the evidence.
你為什么那么做
Why do you do it?
為什么
Why?
你相信你是在做好事嗎
Is it that you believe that you're doing good?
還是你只想取悅你的父親
Or is it that you wish to please your father?
是艾薩克  他瘋了
It's Isaac! He's mad!
不能讓人看見我在這兒
I can't be seen here.
來讓我摸摸
Let me touch you!
起來
Get up!
艾薩克  不要
Isaac, no!
艾薩克  你在干什么
Isaac, what are you doing?
你看到了什么
What do you see?!
艾薩克
Isaac!
你終于來了
Oh there you are!
私通者艾薩克  私通者艾薩克
Isaac the fornicator! Isaac the fornicator!
藏好你們的老婆  藏好你們的羊
Hide your wives! Hide all your sheep!
私通者艾薩克會在他們睡覺時發動襲擊
Isaac the fornicator will get them when they sleep!
私通者艾薩克
Isaac the fornicator!
藏好你們的老婆  藏好你們的老婆
Hide your wives! Hide your wives!
藏好你們的羊
Hide all your sheep!
私通者艾薩克  藏好你們的老婆
Isaac the fornicator! Hide your wives!
-艾薩克  -藏好你們的羊  私通者艾薩克
- Isaac!  - Hide your sheep. Isaac the fornicator.
停下  艾薩克
Stop! Isaac!
約翰森  大事不妙  大事不妙
Jonathan, it's no good. It's no good!
什么不妙
What is no good?
他們看到我們了  他們看到我們了
They saw us. They saw us.
他們看到我們在樹林里
They saw us in the woods.
他們看到我們了
They saw us.
他們看到我們在樹林里  他們看到我們了
They saw us in the woods. They saw us.
閉嘴
Shut up.
把他送進監獄
Take him to the jail.
他們看到我們在樹林里
They saw us in the woods.
他們看到我們了
They saw us.
治安官
Magistrate.
西布里夫人
Mrs. Sibley.
你都干了什么
What have you done?
那個白癡看到了我們在樹林里
The idiot saw us in the woods.
艾薩克
Isaac.
所以你未經我允許就動手了
So, you did this without consent?
他不是一個人
He wasn't alone.
我們會找出和他一起的人  他會被燒死
We'll find out who was with him, and he will burn.
不  你什么都別想做
No, you will do nothing further.
-但是  -別想了
- But... - Nothing!
回家去  治安官
Go home, magistrate.
你身上有股森林的臭氣
You reek of the woods.
把蘿絲找來
Find me Rose.
醉鬼撒酒瘋  僅此而已
A drunken romp, that's all --
年輕人的特權
A young man's prerogative.
但他身上根本沒有酒味
And yet no smell of spirits on him.
那就燒了他  還等什么
Oh, well, burn him, then. Why wait?
如果他被下咒了就不該為自己的行為受罰
If he was spelled, he's blameless in his actions.
那你為什么還關著他
Yet you still hold him. Why?
在他身上找到的
Found on his person.
很可能是偷來對物品的主人下咒的
Likely stolen to cast a spell on its owner.
前一分鐘他是下咒者
One minute, he's speller.
下一分鐘就成了受害者
The next, he's bewitched.
拿個主意吧  牧師
Make up your mind, reverend.
他究竟是巫師還是巫術的受害者
Is he a witch or a victim of the craft?
巫師煉藥的主要成分
Chief ingredient of a witch's brew.
艾薩克帶我進入那片樹林
Isaac took me into those woods.
他冒著生命危險帶我去看那些巫師
He risked his life to show me the witches.
如果他是其中一員為什么要這么做
Why, if he was one?
我給他灌了點
I've, uh, administrated a tonic
能讓他安靜下來  不再發狂的藥劑
that'll settle him down and, uh, end the fits.
以你作為醫師的判斷  你怎么看
What is your surgeon's opinion of the boy's condition?
我不能確定病因
I can't say for sure as to cause or source,
但從他胡言亂語的狀況看
but going by his babble,
那個孩子估計是精神失常了
that boy is good and touched.
我們要盡可能相信他
Every benefit of the doubt,
找出所有可能的原因
every avenue explored.
那個孩子是我們中的一員
The boy is one of our own.
盡管他不被人們接受  遭受唾棄
Outcast and shunned as he may be,
但他依然生活在塞勒姆
he still resides in the bosom of Salem.
我會
I'll, uh --
我會和他單獨聊聊
I'll speak with him personally.
今晚不行
Not tonight, you won't.
為什么
And why not?
蘭姆給艾薩克服食了一些助于入睡的藥劑
Lamb gave Isaac a tonic to help him sleep.
我想您最好早上再來  治安官
Probably best, magistrate, to return in the morning.
是的  治安官
Yes, magistrate.
到時候你可以和他單獨聊聊
You can have your personal talk with him then.
蘿絲  拋開治安官不談
Rose, absent the magistrate,
我有多大機會得到大家的忠誠
what chance have I of harnessing the body's allegiance?
舊派與新派的支持者各有千秋
The others are split between old and new.
很難說這種分歧會帶來什么結果
Difficult to predict the outcome of such a divide.
你年歲不輕
You're old
卻沒有被這種恐懼所支配
and yet somehow not governed by this fear.
區分我們的不是年齡  而是野心
It is not age that divides us, but ambition.
他并非沒有野心
Well, he's not without ambition.
屈從于女人讓他憤懣
It chafes him to bend to a woman,
他之所以仍這么做是為了我們的大義
but he does so that our greater purpose may live.
我們說好了的  由我帶領大家
It was to be me that led us.
沒錯  如今也依然如此
It was and it is.
但如今我的權威卻總受到質問及挑戰
Questioned and challenged at every turn,
每一項決定都會受到懷疑和監視
each and every decision soliciting doubt and scrutiny.
我們再如何渴望
Much as we may wish it,
深淵中也不存在權力
primacy does not live in the abyss.
一切犧牲絕不能白費
It cannot have all been in vain.
西布里
Sibley.
你的孩子
Your baby.
一切犧牲絕不能白費
It cannot have all been in vain.
這種生活  我的
This life, my...
你的選擇
Choices.
有選擇嗎
Was there a choice?
還是我選擇的權力早已被剝奪
Or was choice taken from me?
現在想這些事為時已晚
It's too late now to think of such things.
是嗎
Is it?
再次見到他肯定不容易
It mustn't have been easy seeing him again.
決定權在你  孩子
It is yours to decide, my girl,
這些犧牲會不會白費
what is in vain and what is not.
你會支持我的決定嗎
And you will stand behind my decision?
我會有限度地支持
Up to a point.
主人的根基很深
The magister's roots are old.
他見識過許多也經受了很多痛苦
He has seen much and suffered greatly.
不要低估他
Do not underestimate him.
西布里夫人
Mrs. Sibley.
奧登上尉
Captain Alden.
艾薩克不是巫師
Isaac is not a witch.
你什么都不做的話他就會被絞死
You do nothing, he'll be hung for one.
我們得制止這件事
We have to stop this.
如今的你陡剩一副軀殼
There's nothing left in you.
沒有情感  沒有惻隱之心
No feelings, no heart.
你不再是我曾經認識的那個女孩了
You're not the girl I once knew.
他們審問過他了嗎
Have they questioned him?
還沒有
No.
因為醫師給他喝了安眠藥劑
That's because he was given a sleeping tonic.
所以他什么都沒說
So he's said nothing.
沒說
Nothing.
但是柯頓
But Cotton is eager,
以及治安官都早已迫不及待
and the magistrate was hard to turn away.
霍爾  他也在嗎
Hale? Was there?
他就是去審問他的
He came straight to question him.
相信我  我一定會站在你這邊
You have my complete allegiance.
"行善舉之機會即是我等之天資"
"Our opportunities to do good are our talents."
這是我父親說的
My father said that.
偉大的英克里斯·麥哲
The great Increase Mather.
不偏不倚  公正無私
To stay impartial, to weigh without bias --
這就是我該做的善舉嗎
is this the good I am meant to do?
我不想讓你了斷在我手里
I don't want your life in my hands.
塞勒姆一半的人覺得你是個傻子
Half of Salem takes you for a fool.
剩下的認為你是個齷齪下流之人
The rest dismiss you as a pervert.
是我瘋了嗎  我居然在你身上看到了些什么
Am I mad to think I saw something in you?
一個人們該有的品質
Something of a man?
正是如今這惡魔橫行的塞勒姆所需要的
And just the sort Salem needs to fight the devil.
艾薩克  艾薩克
Isaac, Isaac. Isaac, Isaac.
親愛的艾薩克
Oh, sweet Isaac.
艾比
Abby?
艾薩克
Isaac.
你怎么
How did you --
噓  親愛的
Shh. My sweet.
告訴我
Tell me --
和你在森林里的人是誰
who was with you in the woods?
什么人
Who was what?
那天晚上
The other night.
誰和你在一起
Who was with you?
誰和你在一起  親愛的艾薩克
Who was with you, my sweet Isaac?
誰和你在一起  親愛的
Who was with you, my love?
沒人會聽到的
No one can hear us.
如果你愛我就告訴我
If you love me, you'll tell me.
我不能
I can't.
告訴我  我們就能又在一起了
Tell me, and we'll be together again,
像從前一樣
just like we were.
我不能
I can't.
你可以的
You can.
我不能
I can't.
你不能什么
You can't what?
你可以的  沒事的
You can. It's okay.
誰和你在一起  親愛的
Who was with you, my love?
是約翰·奧登
It was John Alden.
早上好  治安官
Good morning, magistrate.
早上好  西布里太太
Good morning, Mrs. Sibley.
見到您真是意外之喜
What an unforeseen delight.
要和我一起喝點咖啡嗎
Will you join me in some coffee?
我們正在嘗試一種新的巴西咖啡
W-we've been experimenting with a new brazilian brew.
能聊聊嗎
May we speak?
女士們在禱告
The ladies are at prayer.
艾薩克當時是一個人
He was alone -- Isaac.
你審問他了  怎么審的
You questioned him? How?
他一個人在森林里
He was alone in the woods.
不必再為這事煩惱了
And that ends this persecution.
你能確信
And you're absolutely certain
艾薩克說的是實話嗎
that Isaac was telling the truth?
在那種情況下  他絕不會
The circumstances were such that a lie would not --
也不可能撒謊
could not -- cross his lips.
既然這樣
Well, then, that leaves nothing
我們就只能讓行政委員們投票
but to task the selectmen to a vote
以巫師罪絞死那個孩子了
and hang the boy for witchcraft.
不行
No.
少一個蠢貨塞勒姆也不會更悲慘
Salem will be no poorer for one less nitwit.
不行
No.
我們不知道他到底看見了多少
We will never truly know what he saw,
他目擊的一切可能會害死我們
and what he saw could get us all killed.
我能控制艾薩克
I can control Isaac.
大祭典怎么辦
And what of the grand rite?
你需要另一個祭品  而現在就有一個
You wanted another victim, and now you have one.
時不我待  西布里太太
Tick-tock, mrs. Sibley.
下輪滿月很快就到了
The next moon fast approaches.
我不會讓你絞死他的
I will not let this happen.
你無能為力
You're powerless to stop it.
委員會將全力反對
The council will rule overwhelmingly against it.
你不能這么做
You will not do this!
如今能阻止你的只有情感了
It can only be sentiment that's stopping you.
這些猛烈的情感
Such raw emotion.
會成為你致命的弱點
It makes you vulnerable.
別忘了你的初衷
Don't let it cloud your purpose.
他必須死
He has to go.
西布里太太
Mrs. Sibley.
早上好  安
Good morning, Anne.
這些不是我的
They ain't mine.
從禮拜天起我已經用不同方式說過十遍了
I've said it 10 ways from sunday!
那它們怎么會在你身上
Then how did they come to be on your person?
我不知道  一定是豬頭人放在我身上了
I don't know. The pigman must have put them on me.
或是峭壁里那個可怕的怪物
Or that blasted specter from the crags.
豬頭人
The pigman?
他那晚在林子里看到咱們了
He saw us that night in the woods.
所以他們才這么對我
That's why they're doing this to me.
你不明白嗎  他們知道我看到了什么
Don't you see? They know I seen something.
你還記得些什么
What else do you remember?
-樹林里的事嗎  -不是
- From the woods? - No.
是另一個晚上
From the other night.
在...妓院
At -- at the rod
那個窯子嗎
The whorehouse?
沒有  我什么都不記得
Nothing. I-I-I don't remember anything.
我告訴你了
I told you...
上尉  借一步說話
Captain, a word.
霍爾治安官很快會回來找艾薩克
Magistrate Hale will be here soon for Isaac.
他準備強制投票來吊死他
He's prepared to force a vote and hang him.
你必須阻止他
You will stop him.
怎么阻止
How?
不擇手段
Any way you must.
我得去處理塞勒姆的事務了
Well, the business of Salem awaits no man.
我知道你要干什么  這讓我深惡痛絕
I know what you're doing, and I hate you for it.
你這話簡直是大不敬
Unacceptable language.
這種沖動的情緒實在是太可怕了
Utterly and completely horrid sentiment.
我朋友才剛死
My friend is dead.
你就急著去殺另一個
And you rush out to kill another.
親愛的  你必須明白
Darling, you must understand --
就算是瑪麗·西布里
Even Mary Sibley,
一個我從未有過相同意見的人
with whom I share not a single common opinion,
都覺得你的行為很低劣
finds your actions vile!
你覺得你有什么資格
And just how much of my conversation
能夠和我談這個
did you feel yourself entitled to?
至少我知道這樣迫害艾薩克簡直是荒謬至極
Enough to know that this persecution of Isaac is folly!
你要再下毒手嗎  父親
Will you kill another, father?
這就是你急著去處理的"事物"嗎
Is that the "Business" you're so eager to attend to?
我所做的每一件事
Everything I do,
都是為了這個家
I do for this family...
不光為它的安寧
For its well-being
也是為了整個小鎮
and for the greater good of this town.
怎么
What?
沒有"你怎么敢"或是"注意尊長"嗎
No "How dare you?" or "Mind your elders"?
這一次  我的女兒  我支持你
For once, my daughter, I agree with you.
真的嗎
You do?
但如果我是你
But if I were you,
我會拋開對西布里夫人的厭惡
I'd find an avenue around your distaste for Mrs. Sibley
以去學習她的手段和方法
in order to absorb her manners and ways.
她卑鄙無恥  我不可能成為她
She's despicable. I could never be like her.
她是一個擁有自己聲音的女人
She is a woman who has found her way to a voice.
看到她怎么運用了嗎
Look how she uses it.
你也可以隨意使用你的
You could use yours any way you like,
但你首先要找到它
but you have to find it first,
除非你想花余生的時間
unless you want to spend the rest of your life
只對著你父親大吼大叫
shouting at your father...
或者對你的丈夫
Or...your husband.
西布里夫人要干什么
What did Mrs. Sibley require?
如今你相信艾薩克是無辜的還是有罪
Are you convinced of Isaac's innocence or guilt?
我兩種都不確定
I am not convinced of either.
那就別插手
Then stay the hell out of my way.
我們該帶他去接受審判了
We shall take the boy to trial.
那就等于將他送上了絞刑架
That path leads to the gallows.
這不是任何人可掌控的
It's in no one man's hands.
真的  那是誰掌控的
Really? Whose hands is it in?
當然是上帝了
God's, of course.
不
No.
需要我提醒你嗎  孩子
Need I remind you, son,
你所阻撓之人在昨日
that you are impeding the very same man
才剛救了你一命
who only yesterday was your savior?
是啊  不過那是昨天了
Yeah. That was yesterday.
今天你要帶艾薩克走
You want Isaac today...
就必須通過我這關
you got to go through me.
偉大的約翰·奧登  消失了十年后
The great John Alden disappears for a decade
居然還膽敢回來
and then dares to come back
并且插手我們小鎮的事務
and dictate how to run our town?
逮捕他
Take him.
為這個艾薩克這么做不值得
He is not worth this Isaac.
這和艾薩克無關
This has nothing to do with Isaac.
我知道
I know.
也就是說和約翰·奧登有關了
Which means it has to do with John Alden.
治安官將明白誰才是真正的領袖
The magistrate will learn who leads us,
而且他必須接受
and he will accept it.
不然呢
Or?
幫幫他
Help him.
霍爾治安官  你的女兒
Magistrate Hale, your daughter!
住手  把他關回牢里去
Stop! Get him back in the cell!
住手  住手
Stop! Stop!
把他弄回牢房去
Get him back in the cell!
怎么了  發生了什么
What? What's happened?
她有沒有服食任何花園里
Has she eat something strange
-或樹林中的奇怪東西  -沒有
-from the garden or the wood? -No.
她有沒有被蟲子或動物咬傷
Was she bit by an insect or a critter?
沒有  快幫幫她
No, no! Please!...
發生了什么
What's happened?
她不能呼吸了
She -- she can't breathe!
看在上帝的份上  做點什么
For god's sakes, man, do something!
我對此無能為力
She is beyond my arts.
住手
Stop it!
求求你  住手吧
Make it stop!
治安官  下午好啊
Magistrate, good afternoon.
求求你  我會放了艾薩克
I beg of you. Isaac can go free,
全聽你的  求求你停手吧
whatever you want. Just make it stop.
-不許再對他逼供  -不會了
- You will not question him. - No.
別再插手我的事
You will get out of my way.
也不許再質疑我的權威
You will let me lead without further interference.
我將決定誰生誰死
I will choose who lives and who dies.
全聽你的  救救她吧
Yes, yes. Help her.
你要知道  治安官
You see, magistrate,
在這個鎮上我已經失去了值得牽掛的一切
I've lost everything in this town that I ever cared for.
而你
You, however,
你卻有許多害怕失去的事物
You have everything left to lose --
這些情感正是你致命的弱點
a sentiment that makes you vulnerable.
求你了
Please.
放過我女兒
My daughter.
放過我女兒吧
她情況好多了
She's improved.
以前我一直不明白
I never understood it before --
為什么父母忍心把我送走
how my parents could send me away.
有什么會比與家人分離更殘忍
What could be worse than being apart?
肯定不是死亡
Certainly not death.
如今我明白了
Now I know
父母會為了孩子的性命做出任何事情
a parent will do anything for the life of their child.
你做了什么
What did you do?
我是怎么了
What happened?
沒事了  親愛的
It's all right, darling.
一切都會好的
Everything's going to be all right.
說實話
A confession --
有時我不禁會想  或許偶爾來一場毆斗
I've thought, on occasion, my character might've been improved
會對我的性格有所幫助
by the infrequent tussle.
沒錯
Oh, yeah.
你挨過的那些揍還真是讓你獲益良多
Beating's done you a world of good.
你為什么幫我
Why did you help me?
就算是上帝也需要一場公平的斗爭
Even God demands a fair fight.
先生們
Gentlemen.
行政委員和我一致認為  這件案子
The selectmen and I feel, in this particular case,
不需要進行審判與投票
that a trial and a vote will be unnecessary.
顯然  那小伙子只是喝醉了
Clearly, the lad was drunk.
我們同意釋放他  并撤銷一切指控
We are willing to let him go and drop charges.
當然了  除非牧師不這么認為
Unless, of course, the reverend feels otherwise.
就是一場醉酒鬧事罷了
A drunken romp is all --
年輕人的特權
A young man's prerogative.
不如你去告訴他這個好消息吧
Why don't you tell him?
塞勒姆的善良人民
The good folks of Salem
認為你只是喝醉了  而不是一個巫師
have declared you a drunk and not a witch.
你被釋放了
You're sprung.
我自由了
I'm free?
沒錯  趕緊離開這鬼地方吧
Yeah. Get the hell out of here.
從沒有人為我說過話
Pretty sure no one's ever stood for me before.
讓我不知道該說什么好
Makes it hard to know what to say.
你救了我一命
You saved my life.
好消息
Excellent news.
艾薩克被釋放了
Isaac has been spared.
怎么會
What? How?
因為沒有足夠的證據將他定罪
There simply wasn't the required evidence to convict.
我說過我一定會詳細調查
I told you I was thorough
所以只要你是無辜的
And that the innocent...
就根本無需擔心
have no cause for alarm.
這還不足以消除你的憂慮嗎
Does that not give you peace?
這只是今天
That is today,
但未來的日子呢
but what of the days that follow?
無論發生什么  我們會一起面對
We will take them as they come.
我們
We will?
我說過  我不會讓你受到任何傷害
I told you -- no harm will come to you.
你沒法保證
You can't be sure.
我可以
I can.
你是否曾想過
Do you ever wonder?
什么
What?
或許我們可以離開這里
If we could leave this place?
忘了塞勒姆和這些巫師們
If we could forget Salem and its witches?
去過不同的生活
If we could have a different life?
我相信我做的一切都是正義的
I believe I'm doing good.
我知道
I know.
你的父親一定會為你無比驕傲
And your father would be so very proud.
艾薩克被釋放了嗎
Isaac has been freed?
是的
Yes.
那就好
Good.
你真該看看那些民兵的樣子
You should see the militia.
我很感激
I'm grateful.
你對艾薩克的幫助
For Isaac.
不用客氣
Okay, then.
約翰
John...
今天我們只是幸運
We were fortunate today,
但好運不會一直伴隨著我們
but we might not be so lucky in days to come.
如果你堅持留下
If you insist on staying...
你必須明白  我將無法保護你
...you must understand I cannot protect you.